+1 661 478 9651 mlam@nyu.edu markofthelam.com github.com/emceelamb

Brooklyn, New York

Sculptor, media scholar, and educator turned developer, with over five years of experience developing websites and digital design for businesses ranging from e-commerce to independent artists. I take an interdisciplinary approach to interactive media and computer networking technology. My other interests include teaching programming, digital accessibility, and making generative sound objects.

Technical Skills

- · Dynamic Web Development Wordpress, React, VueJS, Flask, Postgres, Mongodb
- · Operations *NIX System Administration, Git, Docker, Squid, Wireshark
- Programming Languages Bash, Node.js, Python, Go, C
- Digital Accessibility Standards WCAG 2.1, Section 508

Professional Experience

2015- MARK OF THE LAM

Freelance Developer, New York City, Ho Chi Minh City, Los Angeles, Berkeley

- Design and develop websites for business ranging from personal artists to independent publishing houses to promote
 products, events and services with clients located in Israel, Qatar, Hong Kong, and United States
- · Implement web features including image api's to online payment procedure to streamline development time
- · Scope timelines and specifications while coordinating with clients to meet business objectives
- · Work with account managers to deploy websites to production, while testing for bugs and errors
- · Technology stacks range from Wordpress, Square Space, Weebly, React, Drupal, Joomla, Magento, and AJAX

2018-2020

New York University - ITP

Graduate Assistant - Web Accessibility Developer, New York City

- Developed an accessibility compliant front-end interface for a project database to meet NYU accessibility initiative guidelines in accordance to WCAG standards
- · Created training materials to conduct accessibility audits with assistive tech including VoiceOver, Jaws, and Lighthouse/WAVE
- Mentored and trained students in web accessible programming paradigms so students will consider impact of
 accessibility in their development career

2018-2019

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts Digital Accessibility Fellow, New York City

- Created internal digital accessibility training material to promote access for a diverse customer base
- Created an automated work process for captioning a catalog of over 1000 hours of video content
- Audited internal and external digital media of a world-class performing arts institution and write recommendations to meet WCAG 2.1 and Section 508 compliance
- · Developed a fully compliant digital map of campus accessibility features to simplify wayfinding

2017-2018

Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology & Education
Visiting Lecturer – Introductory Programming, English, Ho Chi Minh City

- Developed an introductory English/programming curriculum in the C language for non-native English speaking students, and worked with student leaders to promote extracurricular English study
- Led supplemental workshops in specialized programming topics such as web design and portfolio building

Education

May 2020

Interactive Telecommunications, Master of Professional Studies

New York University, New York City

Dec 2015

Media Studies & Art Practice, Bachelor of Arts University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley

May 2013

Graphic Design, Associate of Arts College of the Canyons, Valencia